Hello friends, in today's video, let's completely decode the brochure of the health insurance plan called
Health Shield 360 from IICI Lombard
.   The
main highlight of this is the four
benefits.  Unlimited Reset
Cumulative Bonus Claim Protector
Sum Insured Protector as well as Free and
Post Hospitalization Days Home Health
Care Daily Cash Deductible Discounts
Yesons Waiting Periods are all
explained with real life examples and we will
also tell you whether your health is actually covered by IICI 360°.
IICI Lombard General Insurance
Company is a joint venture between IICI Bank and
Lombard Canada,
which was started in 2001
.  IICI, as you probably
know, stands for Industrial Credit
and Investment Corporation of
India, a private sector bank
.  Lombard comes
from the Lombard Insurance Company in Canada
.  These two companies have jointly
entered the general insurance sector in India.  When it comes to the benefits offered by this policy,
this
IICI Lombard Health Shield 360
plan comes with Summoned Options and
offers from ₹5,00,000 to ₹50,00,000
.  Generally, if the hospitalization lasts
more than 24 hours, the expenses
are covered.  Day care treatments will also
be covered.  That is, for example, if
you
take out a health insurance policy for 5,000,000 and undergo a surgery for 3,000,000, the
hospital bill will be
completely covered.  Also, the
main highlight of this plan
is the unlimited reset benefit, which means that
if the patient is admitted to the hospital and
makes a medical insurance claim, the
health insurance company will either reduce the coverage or
restore the insurance coverage.  They say that it can also be
restored unlimited times
.  So, for example, let's say
you have health insurance coverage for ₹10,000,000
.  However, you
claimed for ₹10,000,000.  Then you will
immediately get fresh coverage for ₹10,000,000 again
.  Even if another claim is made in the same year, it
will be reset again.  But keep in mind that this is
only valid for treatments in India
.  The policy will not expire and
will be refilled again and again.  This option is
fine.  Similarly, the next benefit in this IIC
Lombard Health Shield 360 policy is
for cumulative bonus, meaning that if you do not make
any health insurance claims in one year, an
extra 10% bonus will be added to your health insurance coverage the next year
.  That is, say for
example you took out a policy for ₹10,000,000
.  If you do not make any claim for one year,
what will happen next year? A bonus of Rs. 1 lakh will
be added, meaning that your
health insurance total coverage will
not be Rs. 10,000, but Rs. 100,000. In this way,
10% will be added for every claim-free year,
but the maximum limit is equal to the
base sum insured you have taken, which means it will
increase only up to 100%. That is, if you take a policy for Rs. 10,000,
it will increase only up to a maximum of Rs. 20 lakh.
Keep in mind that if you don't make a claim, your coverage will increase, but only up to a certain limit.  Also, the
next benefit in this policy is claim
protector.  Generally,
insurance coverage is not applicable to some items in hospital bills
.  For
example, there is no coverage for things like gloves, masks, and
consumables
.  But this feature will
also cover items excluded by IRDA
.  They are also related to the claim, so
for
example, if there is a hospital bill of ₹5,000,000 and
non-medical expenses of ₹50,000,
you will have to pay under a normal policy
.  But here the insurance company
pays.  Also, the next benefit in this plan
is the same assured protector.  With this Same Assured Protector feature, if
you pay an extra premium, your
policy coverage
will increase in line with inflation every year.  This means that
as medical costs increase, your
insurance coverage will automatically
increase.  So, for example, let's say
you took a policy for 10 lakhs
.  That means, let's say it was 10 lakh rupees in year one and
now the inflation rate is
10%.
At the time of annual renewal, this 10 lakhs equal in-shot will be added by 10% and will
become 11 lakhs.  Again,
if inflation next year is 8%, then
in year 3, your coverage will be 11 lacs x 8%, which is 11.88 88
lacs.
Coverage continues to increase every year.
But the important thing here is that if you
cancel this feature for a year,
all the extra coverage you have accrued so far will be lost.  Remember this.
Also, the next feature in this policy is the
Super No Claim Bonus.  So, for
example, let's say you
take out a health insurance policy for ₹5,00,000
.  If you have not made any claims under this health insurance policy,
you will not be able to claim for the next year.
Then you will get 50% bonus i.e. ₹
5,000,000 sum insured plus ₹2.5,000,000
super no claim bonus i.e.
how much total coverage will you get 7.5 lock and you will
not be able to claim again in the same year 2.  There is another
50% bonus, which is ₹2.5 locked.  That means
how much will be the total coverage? Now ₹7.5
lakh plus ₹2.5 lakh means the total
coverage will be ₹10,000,000.  This means that
your total coverage will double in just two years
.  If not, here are some
important points.
You will have to pay an extra premium for this benefit called Super No Claim Bonus
.
The cover also increases by 50% for each claim-free year.  The maximum can
even increase up to 100%.  If you claim, your
bonus will be reduced by 50%.  If you cancel the policy
midway, you will lose the entire bonus
.  Also, this plan
covers expenses for 90 days before hospitalization and 180 days after
.  That means, for example, the
insurance
company will cover the tests before surgery, the medicine expenses after surgery, and everything else.  This plan
covers treatment at home rather than hospital admission
.  That is, if you
take home treatment with a doctor's advice, the expenses will be
covered.  Similarly, road ambulance
coverage ranges from 3000 to 5000.
Air ambulance coverage is also available
.  Not only that, but they also offer rewards and benefits for maintaining a
healthy lifestyle through the 360 ​​Wellbeing Program
.
Inpatient hospitalization
is also covered under this policy.  Similarly, when it
comes to outpatient treatment,
insurance covers doctor consultations, medicines, tests, and expenses even if you are not admitted to the hospital
.  But there is a limit here
that depends on the sum of your investment
.  So, for
example, if you take a health insurance policy for ₹5,000,
keep in mind that it will only cover OPD expenses up to ₹2,000.  If
you take a policy of Rs 10 lakh, you will get the same coverage up to Rs 4,000,
or if you take a policy of Rs 50 lakh, you will
only get coverage up to Rs 7,500
.  This means that even if you have a
doctor's bill of ₹3000, the insurance company will
only pay ₹2000 since you have a limit of ₹2000
.   You will have to
pay the remaining 1000 yourself.  This means that daily
medical expenses will be covered,
but the coverage limits are very low
.  Otherwise, this is an add-on cover,
meaning that you have to pay the premium and take advantage of it.  Also,
some treatments are covered in this plan
.  That means cosmetic surgery, obesity
treatment, alcohol-related issues,
but these are also covered.
All of these are standard exclusions,
but that's why I'm saying you should be aware
.  Also, this policy has a
two-year waiting period for pre-existing diseases
.  The initial
waiting period is 30 days.
This is general.  Generally, pre-
existing diseases last up to three years
.  Since there are two years in this,
it is a benefit from the customer's point of view
.  One year has passed, hasn't it?
Similarly, if you have a claim like diabetes as soon as you take out the policy, you can't
do it right away.  You will also have to wait until this two-year period
.  And
finally, my opinion on this IICI Lombard Health
Shield 360 plan is that whenever you
take any kind of health insurance, you should
do three checks compulsorily, which means
first there is the solvency ratio
.  This indicates
how much financial strength the company has to pay claims
.  IICI Lombard
Solvency Ratio in the last three years is
2.46 2.51 2.62, which means that the company's capital
strength is growing strongly
.  If it is more than 1.5,
you
can consider it strong.  Next comes the
claims incurred ratio, which is a
ratio that tells you what percentage of the amount the company pays out as claims if it takes in Rs 100.
If this ratio is generally 75 to 90%, then it is good and fine. For example, if
this ratio is 77, 78, 82%, then it
is 77, 78, 82%.  This claims incurrence ratio can be
said to be in a healthy range because it
also shows that the company pays claims.  At the same time, the premiums are
not extremely high, so the pressure doesn't feel too
much.  Simply
put, the claims experience is
balanced
.  Similarly, now the final
ratio we need to look at
is the claims settlement ratio. The
claim settlement ratio in health claims
is around 85%. That too for the financial year 22,
23, 24, it is 85, 85, which means that in 2425, it
is 97%. This ratio means that if the company
receives 100 claims, how many have been settled?
85% means that 85 have been
settled. 97 means that if 100 claims are received, it has been
settled
.  So if we look at this claim
settlement ratio over the last three years, we can see that the
claim settlement ratio will be good only in the year 2025.   It would have been
good if this ratio had been above 95% for the last three years as well.  But I can't say it's super, but
only those who are willing to take a risk should try this health
insurance policy.
Don't take that risk.  If you don't know what this ratio will be next year,
avoid this health insurance policy.  And if IIC Lombard 360°
has Health Shield coverage or if it has a
95% plus claim settlement ratio
in the last three years,
I would happily and strongly recommend this policy
.  Just because of this ratio alone, I would
say that I did not take out Health Shield cover on this IICI Lombard 360°.   No matter
how good the benefits are, the
customer
will be happy only if the company also delivers on its claims.  So if you want a policy with a 95%
plus claim settlement ratio for the last
three years,
check out the policies I've provided the link in the description.  Also,
if you want
to know about IICI Lombard Elevate Policy, then
check out this video.  If you
liked this video, please like it and
subscribe to our channel now for more banking and personal finance daily videos like this. Thanks
for watching.